

Name: <u>HEZBULLAH</u> <u>SHAH</u> Profession: IT Engineer Visa Status: Employment Mobile No: +971-50-2023270

Email ID: email@hezbullahshah.pk
Web: http://www.hezbullahshah.pk



Enterprise Administrator on Windows Server® 2008 Server Administrator on Windows Server® 2008

<u>IT ENGINEER</u>

MCITP, MCTS, CCNA, RHCE, JNCIA



CAREER LEVEL AND SUMMARY -

Having long career history of more than 3 years in Managing, Supporting, and new installations for Windows Servers, Linux Servers, Windows 7, Windows XP, Windows 98, and MAC. The same also applies for Cisco Routers and Firewalls, ESXi, PHP, MySQL, Hosting (website & Emails) Domain Names Management, SVN Repository System, Apache Configuration, Local Area Networks Installation and support, WiFi, New and existing Rack Servers, remote access of servers and other applications, and more.

PROJECTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS -

- Implementations and Administration of New Servers with Active Directory Domain Controllers, Fax Servers, Print Servers, and File Servers, for Clients like Tasheel Center Khorfakkan, iSolutions etc.
- Implementing different facilities and restrictions through Group Policy for Tasheel Center Khorfakkan.
- Management of Active Directory for Tasheel Center Khorfakkan, iSolutions LLC, DUBAL, and NARC.
- Providing Support for Government, Semi-Government, and Private organizations like Ministry of Environment and Water (MOEW), Tasheel Centers, Abu Dhabi Municipality (ADM), Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank (ADCB), Prime Minister (H.H Sheikh Mohammad) Office, National Avian Research Center (NARC), Two Four 54 (Media Free Zone), Injazat Data Systems, International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA), etc.
- Migrating Windows XP to Windows 7 for Tasheel Center Khorfakkan.
- Bulk migration project of Windows XP to Windows 7 (2000 Computers with 2500 user Profiles) for Dubai Aluminium.
- Implementing Network using Cisco Routers, Cisco Switches, and Cisco Firewalls for Tasheel Center Khorfakkan.
- Implementation of ESXi Server (Virtualizing Servers and Test Environments) at iSolutions LLC.
- Linux Server Implementation for Apache Server, FTP Server, File Server, MySQL Server, and Squid Server
 at iSolutions LLC.
- Direct new and existing Domains (Websites Names) for different hosting and different email services for different clients.
- Install CCTV Setup, Attendance System for different clients.
- Configure remote access through internet for servers CCTV cameras for different clients.
- DNS, DHCP, WINS, configurations for different clients including Tasheel Center Khorfakkan.
- Installation and Administration of Team Foundation Server (TFS) 2010, Visual SVN, Orange HRM for iSolutions LLC.
- Configuring and Administring of WiFi for better usage and coverage at Tasheel Center Khorfakkan, iSolutions LLC, and NARC.
- Preparation of Proposal for tenders of Statistics Center Abu Dhabi and Alain Municipality from iSolutions LLC.
- Network Cable Management at Racks and points at Tasheel Center, MOEW, iSolutions LLC.
- Instructing pupils and guiding them in their LAB Environment at Corvit Institute, Islamabad.
- Preparing educational Labs ISA, IIS, Exchange 2003, DC, ADC installations at Corvit Institute, Islamabad.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

Al Shamalyah Businessmen Services

TASHEEL CENTER, KHORFAKKAN, UAE

Duration: 24th August, 2013 till date (current)

Job Title: IT Administrator

Responsibilities:

- Managing overall IT Servers, routers, firewalls, switches, this was also initially installed and configured by me.
- Guiding and helping the customer services staff and also acting as PRO.

iSolutions LLC, Abu Dhabi, UAE

Duration: 4th March, 2012 to 9th February, 2013 **Job Title: Network & Systems Administrator**

Worked For: Group Head Office (i.e. iMass Investment LLC), Sister Companies (i.e. iSee

Entertainments and Events, iTech Holding), and the company itself.

Responsibilities:

- New installation of Network, Windows and Linux Servers (like Domain Controller, Apache and IIS Web Server, SVN Servers, etc), Storage, Wifi Network, MAC PCs, Windows PCs, and Administring them.

RAQMIYAT LLC, DUBAI, UAE

Duration: 24th January, 2011 to 17 January, 2012

Job Title: <u>IT Engineer</u>

Worked For: Clients - Among many clients, the following were the main clients I worked for:

- Ministry of Environment and Water (MOEW) - Dubai,

- Prime Minister Office - Dubai,

- Abu Dhabi Municipality (ADM) - Abu Dhabi,

- Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank ADCB - Abu Dhabi, Head Office,

Responsibilities:

- Providing Support Services for the clients as well as Administering Servers, Migrations of Windows from Windows XP to Windows 7, PC Deployments, etc and Leading the team at different occasions.

CORVIT SYSTEMS CORVIT SYSTEMS, RAWALPINDI, PAKISTAN

Duration: 5th May, 2010 to 1st October, 2010

Job Title: Internship

Responsibilities: <u>Responsible for the following tasks</u>:

 Instructing and guiding pupils on Windows Server and CCNA Labs for practice work and assisting teachers in preparing LABS.

PTCL PAKISTAN TELECOMMUNICATION LIMITED, BANNU, PAKISTAN

Duration: June 2009 to August 2009

Job Title: Internship

Jobs Performed: DSL & <u>LAN</u>: New Installation & Trouble Shooting of **Internet** and <u>Network</u>.

Decent Net Café Decent Net Café, Bannu, Pakistan

Duration: Feb 2005 to Jan 2010

Job Title: Network and Systems Administrator

Jobs Performed: - Managing Servers (Squid, DHCP, DNS) Routers (Internet Sharing and load

balancing) and Network for clients and Café.

Moon Net Computers Moon Net Computers, Khorfakkan, Sharjah, UAE

Duration: 1999 to January 2004

Job Title: Technician

Jobs Performed: Trouble shooting, and solving the problems of clients on Windows 95,

Windows 98, Windows XP, Office 97, Office XP, Office 2003.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS -

I have Good Knowledge and experience of Support Services for Servers, Clients, and Network. I can easily manage different Windows Server and Client families and different Linux Families too. I am also good on Cisco Routers, firewalls and switches and have knowledge of Juniper Routers.

Also I have very good experience in MS Office, HTML, PHP, and MySQL.

<u>In terms of social skills</u>, I can complete assignments in any kind of challenging work situation. I enjoy working in diverse environments with people from different cultural backgrounds, or in teams either as team-member or team-leader. I am sociable, but I can also work in loneliness if the job nature requires me so.

CERTIFICATIONS OBTAINED -

MCITP (Microsoft Certified IT Professional) Enterprise Administrator on Windows Server 2008 (From Microsoft)

JNCIA (Juniper Network Certified Associate) Enterprise Routing (From Juniper)

TRAININGS OBTAINED -

MCSE (Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer) (From CORVIT SYSTEMS, Rawalpindi, Pakistan)
MCITP (Microsoft Certified IT Professional) (From CORVIT SYSTEMS, Rawalpindi, Pakistan)
RHCE (Red Hat Certified Engineer) (From CORVIT SYSTEMS, Rawalpindi, Pakistan)
CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate) (From CORVIT SYSTEMS, Rawalpindi, Pakistan)
ISO (9001:2008) Internal Auditor Training Course (Conducted by Chiltern TMC)

EDUCATION -

Qualification	Year	Institution
MS (CS) (UNDER PROCESS)	2014-16	SZABIST Dubai, Dubai, United Arab Emirates
BBA-IT (HONORS) (EQUIVALENT TO MASTER	2005-09 ss)	University of Science & Technology Bannu, Bannu, Khyber Pakhtun Khwa, Pakistan
F.Sc. (COMPUTER SCIENCE)	2004	Pakistan Islamia School Fujerah, UAE Affiliated with FBISE, Islamabad, Pakistan
S.Sc. (SCIENCE)	2002	Pakistan Islamia School Fujerah, UAE Affiliated with FBISE, Islamabad, Pakistan

CAREER OBJECTIVE -

To work in a challenging environment where I can prove my abilities and utilize my knowledge to the best interest of the organization.

LANGUAGES -

I have very good command on different languages in terms of speaking, writing, reading, and listening. I have been raised multi-lingual due to living in diverse environments. My native language is both **Pashtu** and **Urdu**. I am educated in **English** through out of my career. Apart from that I have good command on **Arabic** and can speak **Hindi**. However, I cannot read and write Hindi.

Personal Information -

Father Name: Shahzada Khan **Driving License: UAE** and Pakistan **Contact Number:** 00971 50 2023270 Date of Birth: 01.02.1986 Gender: Male **Email:** email@hezbullahshah.pk **Marital Status:** Website: http://www.hezbullahshah.pk Married **Nationality:** Pakistani

ACKNOWLEDGMENT -

I am a hard working person and I try to fulfill and execute all the work entrusted to me on an utmost satisfactory level. I have the ability to work effectively both independently and as a member of a team.

All the above specified information is true to the best of my knowledge.

HEZBULLAH SHAH